Guide to the William Sherman Burgoyne papers circa 1890-1964
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Photographs and postcards, circa 1890-1961; Series E
  - Postcards and souvenir photographs from Holy Land travels., Subseries 1
    - Souvenir photo book of Cairo (Box-folder 13/20)
    - Souvenir snapshots of Cairo (Box-folder 13/21)
    - Souvenir snapshots of the Pyramids (Box-folder 13/22)
- Other materials, circa 1925-1964; Series F
  - Articles and clippings, Subseries 1
    - Clippings re Reverend Paul Roland Ackerman's evasion of the draft, circa 1943 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Clippings re Burgoyne (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Clippings re family members (Box-folder 9/16)
    - Articles and clippings re death and the afterlife (Box-folder 9/17)
    - "If America Enters the War, What Shall I Do?", 1941 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - "The Logic of War", 1941 (Box-folder 9/19)
    - "What Are We Afraid Of?", circa 1950 (Box-folder 9/20)
    - "We Need a WORKING Faith!", 1942 February 12 (Box-folder 9/21)
  - James Henry Burgoyne's certificate of membership to Lents Methodist Church, 1950 April 2 (Box-folder 9/22)
  - Christmas card and letter from Zada and Albert Burgoyne to James Henry Burgoyne, 1948 December 14 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - General ephemera (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Lists of names and addresses, circa 1947 (Box-folder 9/25)
  - William S. and Doris Burgoyne's membership cards, 1940- circa 1954 (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Memorial service program for Elizabeth Bowker, 1955 August 3 (Box-folder 10/2)
    Service in Burgoyne's hometown of Stevensville, Montana, which Burgoyne led. Includes a clipping.
  - Memorial service program for Josephine Caple, 1948 August 24 (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Memorial service program for James Henry Burgoyne, 1951 March 2 (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Memorial service program for Lola Helena Burgoyne, 1959 February 11 (Box-folder 10/5)
  - "The Name and Family of Burgoyne," by Bonnie White, undated (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Names tags, circa 1944, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Laminated obituary for Lola Helena Burgoyne, 1959 February (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Poem about Willamette University, undated (Box-folder 10/9)
    Authorship of poem unclear.
  - Program for Winter Musicn Festival in Hood River, Oregon, circa 1943 (Box-folder 10/10)
    Doris Burgoyne was a member of the choir for the event.
  - Song and play texts, circa 1925-1964 (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Slide with church schedule for Sundays, circa 1935 (Box-folder 17/10)
    Access to this item is restricted.
- Travel lantern slides, 1934; Series G
  Slides made from photographs taken by Burgoyne during his 1934 trip to the Holy Land, North Africa, and Europe. These, alongside commercially-produced slides, were used in Burgoyne's lectures about his travels.
  Access to this series is restricted.
  - New York, Gibraltar, Spain, 1934 February (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Morocco, Algeria, Tunisia, 1934 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Egypt, 1934 March (Box-folder 16/3-16/4)
  - Holy Land, 1934 March (Box-folder 16/5-16/9, 17/1-17/2)
  - France, Greece, Lebanon, Turkey, 1934 (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Italy, 1934 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Uncertain/Unidentified locations, 1934 (Box-folder 17/5-17/9)
    Majority of images in these folders were probably taken in the Holy Land.